You're sure?
妳确定？
With his own eyes, Your Grace.
他亲眼看到的，皇后
Stay here. Tell no one.
留在这里，别告诉任何人
Help me dress.
帮我更衣
Who knows?
有谁知道？
My handmaiden, Talya.
我的侍女，陶雅
Some of the servants.
还有一些仆人
I saw him last night...
我昨晚去见了他
before he--
就在他…
He told me he wished for Aegon to be king.
他跟我说他希望伊耿成为国王
It is the truth.
是真的
Uttered with his own lips.
他亲口说的
His last words to me and I was the only one to hear it.
他临终前对我说的 我是唯一听见的人
And now he's dead.
现在他死了
What is it that could not have waited an hour?
有什么事连一小时都等不了？
Was Dorne invaded?
冬恩人入侵吗？
The King is dead.
国王死了
We grieve for Viserys the Peaceful...
我们为和平之王韦赛里斯哀悼
our sovereign...
我们的君主
our friend.
我们的朋友
But he has left us a gift.
但他留给我们一个礼物
With his last breath, he impressed upon the Queen his final wish:
他咽下最后一口气前 跟皇后说了他的遗愿
that his son, Aegon...
他的儿子伊耿…
should succeed him as Lord of the Seven Kingdoms.
该继承七大王国之主的位子
Then we may proceed now with the full assurance
那我们应该在他的恩准下
of his blessing on our long-laid plans.
执行我们长久以来的计划
Yes. There is much to be done,
是的，如我们先前讨论
as we've previously discussed.
还有很多事要办
Now, there are two among the captains
都城守备队中
of the City Watch that remain loyal to Daemon.
还有两个队长对戴蒙效忠
Let us replace them. Lord Lannister.
我们得换掉他们，兰尼斯特大人
The Treasury is well in hand.
财库很安全
The gold will be divided for safekeeping.
金子将分开保管以策安全
Let ravens be sent to our allies, Riverrun and Highgarden.
派渡鸦通知我们的盟军 奔流城以及高庭…
Am I to understand that members of the small council
现在御前会议的诸位大人
have been planning secretly to install my son without me?
没有跟我商量 就已经在密谋让我儿子继承了？
My Queen, there was no need to sully you with darkling schemes.
皇后，您不需要卷入这邪恶的计划
I will not have this.
我不允许这种事
To hear that you are plotting
听你们密谋用个冒名顶替者
to replace the King's chosen heir with an imposter!
取代国王已选好的继承人
His firstborn son is hardly an imposter.
他的长子根本不是冒名顶替者
Hundreds of lords and landed knights swore fealty to the Princess.
数百位大人以及骑士宣誓效忠公主
That was some 20 years ago. Most of them now dead.
那是二十几年前的事了 大多数的人都死了
You heard the Lord Hand.
御前首相说了
Plot or no, the King changed his mind.
不论是不是密谋，国王改变心意了
I am six-and-seventy years old.
我已经七十六岁了
I have known Viserys longer than any who sit at this table.
我认识韦赛里斯 比在座的任何一位都久
And I will not believe that he said this on his deathbed, alone,
我不相信他在病榻上说出这句话 身旁没有别人
with only the boy's mother as a witness.
只有那孩子的母亲在侧
This is seizure!
这是窃取
It is theft! It is treason!
这是篡位，这是叛国罪
-At the least, it is-- -Mind your tongue, Lyman.
－起码的… －注意你的言词，林曼
The King was well last night...
大家都说昨晚国王
by all accounts.
状况很好
Which of you here can swear that he died of his own accord?
在座谁能发誓他是自然死亡的？
Which of us are you accusing of regicide, Lord Beesbury?
你是在指控我们哪一位弒君 毕斯柏里大人？
Whether it was one of you, or all of you, I care not.
不论是你们其中一位或是所有人，我不在乎
-I will have no part-- -Sit down!
－我不会参与…－坐下
Ser Criston.
克里斯顿爵士
Throw down your sword and remove your cloak, Ser Criston.
放下你的剑，脱下你的袍子 克里斯顿爵士
I am your Lord Commander, Ser Criston.
我是你的总队长，克里斯顿爵士
Cast down your sword.
剑放下
I will not suffer insults to Her Grace the Queen.
我绝对无法容忍对皇后的任何侮辱
There was no insult to me, Ser Criston. Put aside your blade.
我没有被侮辱，克里斯顿爵士，放下你的剑
-Has it come to this? -Lord Commander, enough.
－一定要这样吗？ －总队长，够了
-Let us have Lord Beesbury removed. -No.
－我们把毕斯柏里大人抬走吧 －不
The door remains shut until we finish our business.
待一切谈妥前都不能开门
Storm's End is of concern.
我们得顾忌风息堡
We may not assume the loyalty of Lord Borros.
我们无法确定博洛斯大人站在哪一边
But he has four daughters, all of them unmarried.
但他有四个女儿，全都尚未嫁人
-The right proposal-- -What of Rhaenyra?
－适当的提亲… －雷妮拉怎么办？
The former heir cannot, of course, be allowed to remain free
当然，不能放前任继承人自由
and draw support to her claim.
好让她寻求支持来夺权
-You mean to imprison her. -She and her family
－你的意思是要囚禁她－她与她的家人
will be given the opportunity
会有机会
to publicly swear obeisance to the new King.
公开宣誓对新国王效忠
She will never bend the knee.
她绝对不会屈服的
Nor will Daemon, which you know.
戴蒙也不会，你很清楚
You plan to kill them.
你打算杀了他们
And all here accede to this.
你们全都同意这件事？
Your father is correct, Your Grace.
令尊说得没错，皇后
A living challenger invites battle and bloodshed.
放挑战者活路 只会招来战争与流血冲突
It is unsavory, yes.
这么做确实不道德
But a sacrifice we must make to secure Aegon's succession.
这是为了确保伊耿能顺利继承 而必须做出的牺牲
And then there is Daemon to consider.
还有戴蒙要考虑
-The King wouldn't wish for any unsavory-- -But the King did not wish
国王不会希望任何… 国王不会希望
for the murder of his daughter!
别人杀了他的女儿
He loved her. I will not have you deny this.
他爱她，我不容许你否认
-And yet-- -One more word and I will have you removed
－但是… －再说一个字
from this chamber and sent to the Wall!
我就把在座的送去绝境长城
What do you suggest, Your Grace?
妳有什么建议，皇后？
Time is of the essence.
时间紧迫
Lord Commander Westerling...
维斯特林总队长
take your knights to Dragonstone.
带你的骑士前往龙石岛
Be quick and be clean.
动作要迅速并且利落
I am Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
我是御林铁卫总队长
I recognize no authority but the King's.
我只听命于国王
And until there is one...
新国王即位之前
I have no place here.
这里没有我的职责
It is our fate, I think, to crave always what is given to another.
人总是觊觎他人所拥有的 这是我们的宿命
If one possesses a thing, the other will take it away.
有人拥有一个东西 另一个人就会想夺走
Yes, Princess.
是的，公主
Where is Aegon?
伊耿人呢？
Not here.
不在这里
He's not in his rooms.
不在他的房间里吗？
Father.
父亲…
What's happened?
发生什么事？
-Your father-- -There is a beast beneath the boards.
－你父亲… －小心木板后的猛兽
Oh, my dearest love.
亲爱的…
Ser Erryk.
伊利克爵士
Where's the Prince?
王子人呢？
Forgive me, Lord Hand. I do not know.
请原谅我，御前首相，我不知道
But you're sworn to protect him.
但你发誓要保护他
He exploits his authority to order me away,
他命令我离开
and then he evades me, my Lord.
然后他就逃脱了，大人
I believe he may have left the Keep secretly,
他应该是偷偷离开红堡
gone into the city.
去了城里
Find him.
去找他
Take no one else but your brother.
跟你的兄弟一起去
And remove your white cloaks.
脱下你的白袍
None can know who you are or what you seek...
不能让任何人知道你是谁 或是你的目的
including the Queen.
皇后也不行
My Lord.
是的，大人
Bring him to me, and me alone, Ser Erryk.
只准带他来见我，伊利克爵士
What is the meaning of this?
这是怎么回事？
Guard. Guard!
侍卫 侍卫！
Prince Aegon's not to be found within the castle walls, Your Grace.
城堡内遍寻不着伊耿王子，皇后
Your father has sent Ser Erryk into the city to find him.
令尊派伊利克爵士进城去找他
Ser Erryk knows Aegon. He has the advantage.
伊利克爵士认识伊耿，那是他的优势
I trust again to you, Ser Criston, and to your loyalty.
克里斯顿爵士，我再次相信你 以及你的忠诚
Aegon must be found, and he must be brought to me.
一定要找到伊耿，并且带他来见我
The very fate of the Seven Kingdoms depends on it.
七大王国的命运就靠你了
Everything you feel for me as your Queen.
你对我的感情，身为你的皇后…
I will not fail you.
我不会让妳失望
I'll come with you.
我跟你一起去
That would not be my desire, Aemond.
我不要你去，伊蒙德
-If anything has happened-- -Cole needs me, Mother.
－如果出了任何事…－科尔需要我，母亲
Ser Erryk isn't the only one who knows Aegon's doings.
伊利克爵士不是唯一熟悉伊耿的人
Aegon brought me to the Street of Silk on my thirteenth name day.
我的第十三命名日那天 伊耿带我来丝街
It was his duty as my brother, he said,
他说那是他身为兄长的职责
to ensure I was as educated as he was.
确保我跟他一样受教
At least that's what I understood him to mean.
至少这是我理解的意思
I don't follow.
我不懂
He said, “Time to get it wet.”
他说「该寻欢了」
Every woman is an image of the Mother, to be spoken of with reverence.
每一个女人都是圣母的象征 必须好好尊敬
Sometime last night, we... misplaced our drinking companion.
昨晚我们不小心跟酒友走散了
Knowing that he has been, in the past, a patron of your fine establishment,
就我们所知，他曾是贵宝地的老主顾
we thought to inquire here as to his whereabouts.
我们想问问他的下落
And describe him.
他长什么样子？
That is a delicate matter.
这有点敏感
You see, the man we seek is the young Prince Aegon.
我们要找的人是伊耿王子
I may trust, I hope, in the discretion of your trade.
我相信妳能保守秘密
The Prince is not here.
王子不在这里
Has he been here? Earlier, perhaps?
他有来过吗？也许稍早来过？
-Quite a bit earlier. Years ago, in fact. -But more recently?
－那可早了，是几年前的事－但最近呢？
He does not frequent the Street of Silk.
他不常出入丝街
His tastes are known to be...
他的品味是出了名的…
less discriminating.
朴实无华
Meaning what?
什么意思？
I wish you luck, good Ser. And my best to your friend.
希望你顺利找到他，爵士，也祝福你的朋友
How you've grown.
你长大不少
Viserys amended his wishes.
韦赛里斯修改了遗愿
It's as simple as that.
就这么简单
You once swore your banners to Rhaenyra.
你们曾经宣誓效忠雷妮拉
You must now pledge them to the future king.
现在必须宣誓效忠未来的国王
I must confer first with my house on this matter.
这件事我必须先与家族商量
You'll not leave this room without declaring your intention.
不表明立场就不能离开这里
I am no oath breaker.
我不会违背我的誓言
I will not bend the knee.
我不会屈服
Anyone else?
还有其他人吗？
House Fell keeps its sworn oath to the Princess.
费尔家族 继续遵守效忠公主的誓言
Very well.
非常好
Long live the King.
国王万岁
It seems you were mistaken as to Aegon's habits.
看来你误会了伊耿的习惯
He could be in the hands of mercenaries,
他可能被佣兵掳走
on a ship to Yi Ti.
上了前往夷地的船
He could be dead.
他可能死了
Let us hope, for your mother's sake, that is not the case.
为了你母亲着想 希望情况不至于如此
Let's have a look.
给我看看
-Go on. -Come here. Come here!
－上场吧－过来，过来
Get in there, you little--
给我进去
Yeah!
耶
Come on!
上啊
How old are they?
他们年纪多大？
About 10 years, I should say.
我猜大概十岁
They have them grow their nails and file the teeth.
他们把孩子们的指甲留长，锉利牙齿
Makes them more formidable.
让他们更具攻击性
Come on!
快上
Prince Aegon spends many a night in this place.
伊耿王子经常在夜里跑来这里
Do you see now what he is?
了解他是什么样的人了吗？
You've not seen everything.
这只是冰山一角
Aegon's? One of many, I'd wager.
－伊耿的吗？ －我猜只是其中之一
Here I am, trawling the city, ever the good soldier
我这样一个优秀的士兵
in search of a wastrel who's never taken half an interest in his birthright.
来城里寻找对继承权 一点都不感兴趣的懒虫
'Tis I the younger brother who studies history and philosophy,
而身为他的弟弟，我研读历史、哲学
it is I who trains with the sword,
勤练武术
who rides the largest dragon in the world.
骑乘世上最大的龙
It is I who should be--
我才是该成为…
I know what it is to toil for what others are freely given.
我懂辛苦谋求 他人不费力气得来的东西是什么感觉
And we can't find him, Cole.
我们找不到他，科尔
You are a decent man with no taste for depravity.
我们是不屑堕落的体面之人
His secrets are his own...
他有他自己的秘密
and he's welcome to them.
他可以尽管保有那些秘密
I'm next in line to the throne.
我是下一个顺位的继承人
Should they come looking for me,
要是有人来找我
I intend to be found.
我倒是很乐意被找到
Something must be done. Aegon is unfit to rule.
我们得想想办法，伊耿不适合当王
You tolerated the Prince's proclivities for years.
你纵容王子这么多年
Because it was my sworn duty, Arryk.
因为我宣誓过，那是我的义务
It's for the Hand to find wisdom.
提供睿智建言是御前首相的责任
We swore an oath of service until death.
我们宣誓要至死效忠
A moment of your time, m'lords.
大人，能借一步说话吗？
You'll find no buyers for your wares here.
我们不会买妳的东西
I can take you to Prince Aegon.
我可以带你们去找伊耿王子
Rather, I am sent by one who knows where he is.
知道他下落的人派我来的
Who'll tell you, for a price.
肯答应条件，那个人就会告诉你们
Deliver him, and we'll consider your price.
叫那个人过来，我们会考虑跟他交易
My mistress will not treat with the servants of the Keep...
我家小姐不会与红堡的仆人交易
exalted though they may be.
不管你们的身份有多高尚
She'll trust this to the Hand of the King only.
她只信任国王的御前首相
Impossible.
不可能
I think he will wish to hear what the White Worm can tell him.
我想他会想听听白虫有什么话要说
Halt! Hold the gate!
停，守住大门
Let go of me!
放开我
He was fleeing from the gate.
他打算从大门逃走
Do you know who I am?
你们知道我是谁吗？
A warning for the Princess, I'd wager.
我猜是要去警告公主
What say you?
你有什么话要说？
The Lord Confessor presumes.
那是御前审问长的臆测
I have no love for the Princess.
我不喜欢公主
And where were you going then with such urgency?
那你急着要去哪里？
Let the King's Justice take him.
让御前执法官处理吧
Let go of me!
放开我
-No! This is not right! -You did well, Lord Larys.
－不可以这样－你做得很好，拉里斯大人
-I will-- -Only my duty, my Lord Hand.
我只是…尽我的职责，御前首相大人
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁
You've spent many hours with the Queen of late.
你最近经常随侍在皇后身边
There's no reason those hours could not, in the end, benefit you.
那些时光最终会为你带来好处
I will do you the considerable courtesy of assuming
我相信妳今早如此无礼地对待我
there is a good reason for the outrage of my treatment here this morning.
一定有很好的理由
My sincerest regrets for the lack of ceremony.
很抱歉我必须这么做
The King.
国王
And you are usurping the throne.
妳打算篡夺王位
It was my husband's dying wish.
那是我夫君临终前的遗愿
Believe it or no, it is of no consequence.
妳相不相信都不重要
Aegon will be king.
伊耿会成为国王
I came here to ask your support.
我来寻求妳的支持
Well, I must credit you for your boldness.
那我不得不欣赏妳的勇敢
House Velaryon has long allied itself
瓦列利安家族长久以来
with the Princess Rhaenyra and what has it gained you?
都站在雷妮拉公主那一边，这对妳有什么好处？
Your daughter dead... alone in Pentos.
妳的女儿孤独地死在潘托斯
Your son cuckolded.
妳儿子的妻子外遇
Rhaenyra's heirs are none of yours.
雷妮拉的孩子都不是妳的后代
It is your husband who grasps so heedlessly for the throne.
妳丈夫不顾一切抓着王位不放
And even he has abandoned you:
而连他都抛弃了妳
gone these six long years to fight a desperate battle,
离开六年去打一场危险的仗
returning grievously, if not mortally, wounded,
就算不死也是重伤回来
leaving the Lady of Driftmark to chart her course alone.
让潮头岛夫人独自面对
The word of my house is not fickle.
我们家族的人不会出尔反尔
No. But, dear cousin...
没错，但亲爱的堂姐…
you more than any soul alive understand what I say now.
妳比任何人都明白我现在所说的
Princess Rhaenys, I loved my husband, but I will speak the truth we both know.
雷妮丝公主，我爱我的丈夫 但我要说出我们都知道的真相
You should've been queen.
妳该成为女王的
I little thought to hear those words from you.
没想到妳会说这种话
The Iron Throne was yours by blood and by temperament.
不论是血脉或是性格 铁王座当初都该由妳继承
Viserys would've lived his days a country lord,
韦赛里斯本来该过着乡村仕绅的日子
content to hunt and study his histories,
成天打猎、阅读历史就满足
but... here we are.
但木已成舟
We do not rule but we may guide the men that do.
我们没有统治权 但我们能够引导统治者
Gently...
慢慢地
away from violence and sure destruction and instead toward peace.
远离暴力与无法避免的毁灭 步向和平
Is it in the name of peace that you've imprisoned me?
妳是以和平之名囚禁我吗？
-And what of my dragon? -If we are overmatched,
－那我的龙呢？－如果我们势力悬殊
Rhaenyra will be tempted to strike us, and war will ensue.
雷妮拉一定会想攻击我们，引发战争
Without your dragon, she may be persuaded to negotiate.
没了妳的龙，她也许会被迫进行协商
If it's Driftmark you want, you shall have it
如果妳要潮头岛就给妳
for you and your granddaughters to pass on as you see fit.
给妳和外孙女，妳想传给谁都可以
You are wiser than I believed you to be...
妳比我想象的还聪明
Alicent Hightower.
阿莉森海塔尔
A true queen counts the cost to her people.
真正的皇后在乎人民的性命
And yet you toil still in service to men.
而妳却努力服侍着男人
Your father, your husband, your son.
妳的父亲、妳的丈夫、妳的儿子
You desire not to be free,
妳不想自由
but to make a window in the wall of your prison.
而是在妳的监牢的墙上凿扇窗
Have you never imagined yourself...
妳从没想过自己
on the Iron Throne?
登上铁王座吗？
I'll leave you with your thoughts.
我让妳思考一下
Ring the bell when you have an answer.
有答案的时候再叫我
My Prince.
王子殿下
You yourself are the mysterious White Worm, I take it.
我想你就是神秘的白虫吧？
Or are you simply a further peel in this stinking onion?
还是主使者另有其人？
My condolences on the passing of your king.
很遗憾你们的国王驾崩了
Where is Prince Aegon?
伊耿王子在哪里？
I thought, the Prince is in Flea Bottom where no one is to be trusted.
我担心王子身处 没人可以信任的跳蚤窝里
I'd best secrete him somewhere safe... in case they come looking for him.
最好把他藏在安全的地方 免得有人来找他
Where's the Prince?
王子在哪里？
He is safely tucked away.
他在一个非常安全的地方
I want an end to the savage use of children in Flea Bottom.
孩子们在跳蚤窝里 受的残酷剥削必须终结
They are forced to fight, and worse...
他们被迫打斗，或是被更糟糕地对待
your gold cloaks take the bribes given them to look away.
你们这些金袍子 接受贿赂，故意忽视这件事，令人发指
An obscenity either tolerated or ignored by the crown.
而国王不是容忍就是忽视
I'll look into it.
我会调查
You have my word.
我向妳保证
When your plots ripen
你的计划成功
and you install your grandson on the throne,
让你外孙继承王位时
remember it was me who put him there.
记住，是我让他当上国王的
I could have killed him as easily as a wasp on fruit.
我大可以轻而易举地杀了他 就像打死水果上的黄蜂
There is no power but what the people allow you to take.
权力都是人民赋予的
I will remember.
我会铭记在心
Listen.
你听
No... No!
不，不
No!
不
Where is the White Worm?
白虫在哪里？
She sold you for a price.
她出卖了你
And why have you paid it?
那你们为何要答应她的条件？
I want my mother.
我要见我母亲
Your grandfather, the Hand, will meet you outside the city walls.
你的外祖父，御前首相，要在城墙外见你
You flee what other men die seeking, Aegon.
你逃离了其他人 求之不得的东西，伊耿
I do regret this, friend.
我真的很抱歉，朋友
No! Stop! No.
不…
-I was hoping you disappeared. -Is our father truly dead?
－我本来希望你消失了 －父亲真的死了？
Yes... and they're going to make you king.
是的，他们要立你为王
-No! -Are you going to help me?!
－不要 －你要帮我吗？
No! Let me go!
不，放开我
Where's your brother, huh?
你兄弟呢？
Let me go!
放开我
Brother!
弟弟
Let me go!
放开我
I have no wish to rule!
我不想治国
No taste for duty! I'm not suited.
我不想履行义务，我不适合
You'll get no argument from me.
这点我同意
You let me go, I will find a ship and sail away,
让我走，我会找一艘船，离得远远的
never to be found.
永远不会有人找到我
The Queen awaits.
皇后在等着
-Well played. -None of this is a game.
－很厉害－这不是游戏
And yet you treat it as one.
但妳还是把它当成了游戏
A charming contest,
迷人的竞争
the prize, a pouch of silver.
奖励是一小袋银子
We have relied on one another these many years.
这么多年来我们彼此依赖
And now it is the good of the family that we both desire.
现在都是为了我们的家族着想
Whatever our differences, our hearts remain as one.
不论我们有什么歧见 我们都是一条心
Our hearts were never one.
我们从来就不是一条心
I see that now.
我现在明白了
Rather, I have been a piece that you moved about the board.
我只是你棋盘上的一颗棋子
If that is true, then I made you Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
就算真的是那样 我也让妳当上了七大王国的皇后
-Would you have desired it otherwise? -How could I know?
－难道妳不想吗？ －我怎么知道？
I wanted whatever you impressed upon me to want.
都是你在告诉我，我想要什么
And now the debt comes due.
现在该还债了
-A debt you were happy enough to pay. -A sacrifice.
－你乐于付出的代价 －是牺牲
A sacrifice made for the stability of the realm.
为了维持全境稳定而做的牺牲
No king has ever lived that hasn't had to forfeit
没有国王不曾为了 保护大多数人的性命
the lives of a few to protect the many.
牺牲少数人的性命
Though I understand your squeamishness.
虽然我了解妳很懦弱
Reluctance to murder is not a weakness!
拒绝杀人并非懦弱
I have Aegon.
伊耿在我手上
We'll proceed now as I see fit.
由我说了算
We will send terms to Rhaenyra on Dragonstone.
我们开出条件，送去龙石岛给雷妮拉
True terms, such that she may accept without shame.
真正的条件 让她愿意接受又可以保留尊严
If she lives, her allies will mass behind her banners,
如果让她活着，她的盟友会支持她
-looking for her return. -Then she must not return.
－等着她回归－不让她回归就好
My husband would have desired this mercy be shown
我夫君会希望对他女儿
-to his daughter. -Your husband?
－手下留情－妳的夫君？
Or you, his daughter's childhood companion?
还是妳，他女儿的儿时玩伴？
Criston Cole will be named Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
克里斯顿科尔会被任命为 御林铁卫总队长
My son will be anointed tomorrow at dawn.
我儿子会在明日破晓时加冕为王
The whole of King's Landing must witness his ascent.
整个君临必须见证他登基
He will assume authority. There will be no more dithering.
他会继任王权，刻不容缓
My son will take the crown of his namesake, the Conqueror,
我儿子会以征服者之名继任国王
and carry Blackfyre, his sword.
握着他的剑，黑火
Let the people remember the ancient strength of House Targaryen.
让大家记得坦格利安家族的古老力量
You look so much like your mother in certain lights.
妳某些时候跟妳母亲好像
As you wish.
悉听尊便
Your Grace.
皇后
The hour is late, Lord Larys.
拉里斯大人，现在很晚了
I've found out something that you should know.
我发现了一件妳该知道的事
Have you asked yourself, I wonder...
不知道妳是否问过自己
how it is...
怎么会是…
that your father, the Hand...
妳父亲，御前首相
found Aegon first?
先找到伊耿？
There is a web of spies at work in the Red Keep.
红堡内到处都是眼线，密如蜘蛛网
Along its threads travels news of all our doings.
我们的所作所为 都沿着蜘蛛网线散布出去
Your father knows this, but has left it in place.
妳父亲知情 却放任不管
More than once, it has proved advantageous to those willing to...
多次都为传递小道消息之人
feed the weaver.
带来好处
And this weaver watches me?
而幕后主使者正在监视我吗？
One of the little spiders is your lady-in-waiting.
其中一只小蜘蛛就是服侍妳的仆人
-Talya? -There are more like her.
－陶雅？ －还有更多像她一样的人
Even I do not know their number.
连我都不知道有多少
There is one way to destroy his advantage.
有一种方法能让他不再占有优势
It must be taken out at the head.
擒贼得先擒王
When the Queen dies, the bees fly without purpose.
蜂后死时，群蜂会毫无目的地乱飞
Begging your pardon for the turn of phrase, Your Grace.
抱歉我举例失当，皇后
I assume this task falls within your expertise.
我想你能胜任这任务吧？
If you wish it...
如果妳希望如此…
it will be done.
这件事绝对能办妥
Out of my way!
给我滚开
With me, Princess.
跟我来，公主
I cannot let this treachery stand.
我不能容忍这样的背叛
-Where are we? -Just south of King's Way.
－这里是哪里？－君路的南方
The Blackwater's this way.
黑水河在这边
I won't leave Meleys.
我不会丢下梅丽斯
-If I could get to the Dragonpit, then-- -No.
－要是我能到龙穴… －不行
They'll expect you there, Princess.
公主，他们会在那里等妳
You won't get past the gates.
妳连大门都进不了
Now come.
不，跟我来
You must make for the riverfront and find a ship.
在他们发现妳消失之前，妳必须到河边
Before they know you've gone.
找到一艘船
Move it! Go! Go!
快走开
This way!
这边
Keep moving! That's right.
继续走
That's right!
那边…
-Onward! -This way.
－往前走 －这边
Halt! Halt!
立定，立定
Keep moving!
继续走
All of you, move forward!
所有人往前走
Keep moving!
继续走
Out of the way!
走开
Have the decency to look grateful.
至少表现得心怀感激一点
Do you know what has been done to give you this day?
你知道我为了今天这日子 付出了多少努力吗？
In an hour, you will be king.
再一小时，你就要登基为王
-And my father never wanted this. -That's not true.
－我父亲绝对不愿意－才不是这样
He had 20 years to name me heir and never did.
他有二十年的时间任命我为继承人 但从没这么做过
Steadfastly, he upheld Rhaenyra's claim.
他始终坚持让雷妮拉来继承
He changed his mind.
他改变心意了
No...
不可能
He could have, but he never did
他是可以，但他没有
because he didn't like me.
因为他不喜欢我
And yet, with his final breath,
但他咽下最后一口气时
he whispered to me that you should take his place on the throne.
他轻声跟我说你该继承他的王位
-Do not toy with me, Mother. -I speak the truth.
－别耍我，母亲－我说的是实话
Listen to me, Aegon.
听我说，伊耿
Your grandfather, the Hand, will try to impress on you
你的外祖父，御前首相
that Rhaenyra should be put to the sword.
会跟你说该杀死雷妮拉
You must reject this counsel.
你必须拒绝这个建言
We must not rule with cruelty and callousness.
我们不可以用残忍无情的手段来治国
For all her faults, she is your sister, your father's daughter--
尽管她有错，她还是你的姐姐 你父亲的女儿…
Do you love me?
妳爱我吗？
You imbecile.
你这傻瓜
Make way for the royal wheelhouse!
皇家马车经过
Hey, hey, forward then.
让开
Go on, move yourself! Come on!
快，快走，快点
People of King's Landing...
君临的子民
today is the saddest of days.
今天是最难过的日子
Our beloved king...
我们钟爱的国王
Viserys the Peaceful...
和平之王韦赛里斯
is dead.
驾崩了
But it is also the most joyous of days...
但今天也是最欢乐的一天
for as his spirit left us...
因为在他临终前
he whispered his final wish:
他轻声说出了遗愿
that his firstborn son, Aegon...
也就是让他的长子，伊耿
should succeed him.
继承他的王位
Guards!
侍卫！
Out of the way! Move!
－走开 －快走开
Halt!
立定
Turn!
转身
Present...
准备…
arms!
举剑
It is your great good fortune
你们能在此目睹如此盛典
and privilege... to be here to witness this:
是莫大的幸运和殊荣
a new day for our city...
今天是全城崭新的一天
a new day for our realm.
全境崭新的一天
A new king... to lead us.
有了新国王来率领我们
May the Warrior give him courage.
愿战士赐予他勇气
May the Smith lend strength to his sword and shield.
愿铁匠赐予他盾剑之力
May the Father defend him in his need.
愿天父在他需要时守护他
May the Crone lift her shining lamp and light his way to wisdom.
愿老妪高举祂明亮的灯 指引他走向智慧
The crown of the Conqueror, passed down through generations.
征服者的王冠传了数代
Let the Seven bear witness:
请七神见证
Aegon Targaryen is the true heir to the Iron Throne.
伊耿坦格利安是铁王座真正的继承人
All hail His Grace, Aegon,
恭贺国王陛下
Second of his Name,
伊耿二世
King of the Andals and the Rhoynar and the First Men,
安达尔人、洛恩人与先民的国王
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms
七大王国之主
and Protector of the Realm.
以及全境的守护者
Aegon the King!
伊耿国王万岁
Aegon the King! Long live Aegon!
伊耿国王万岁 伊耿国王万岁
Open the doors!
开门
快开门
Get Helaena.
保护海伦娜